Aswinkumar Prakashkumar

1630 228TH ST SE APT I106, BOTHELL, WA, 98021 aswinkumar.p@outlook.com | 612-469-1282







Summary:

Senior Systems Engineer (Reliability Engineering) with over 7 years of experience in managing a wide variety of Infrastructure and Application stack. I am passionate about Cloud, Automation and the way they have enabled industries to focus more on the guests rather than spending time fixing their infrastructure.

Technology Skills:

Infrastructure Skills Server Administration, Performance Monitoring, Virtualization, Automation,

VoIP, Deployment and Release Management, Chef / Ansible, AWS / Terraform

Monitoring App-Dynamics, Splunk, Data Dog, Grafana, SCOM, and Sensu

Incident, Change, & Problem Management **Service Management Scripting** Python, PowerShell, Shell, Ruby, XML

Professional Experience:

T-Mobile | Senior Site Reliability Engineer **Responsibilities:**

May 2019 – Present

- Monitor Speech IVR infrastructure, systems and application performance/capacity to ensure 24x7 reliability.
- Be a champion and lead efforts for updating infrastructure/application to new versions.
- Identify and automate manual workarounds, process improvements, incident recovery and alerting.
- Identify and troubleshoot reliability, performance and production issues by partnering with different teams.
- Part of a team responsible for Hardening, Simplification and Pruning of IVR System handling 1 M Calls / day.

Target | Guest Reliability Engineer

March 2016 - May 2019

- **Responsibilities:**
- Develop scripts / tools to automate regular provisioning, and incident recovery using various tools for VoIP
- Install, Configure and Administer VoIP Product Suite across the organization (Stores / DC's / Offices / HQ's)
- Work with different stake holders to resolve production issues to ensure the systems are available and reliable.
- Identify opportunities for process improvements, either by automating or leveraging latest technology.
- Was responsible for reducing the overall device footprint by over 60% in over 1800 stores, across the US.

Target | System Reliability Engineer

August 2012 – March 2016

Responsibilities:

- Audit infrastructure for performance bottlenecks, threshold breaches to ensure infrastructure is available 24x7.
- Install, Manage and Administer Virtualization Tools, Hyper-V, SCVMM, VMWare, Citrix Xen Product Suite.
- Automate laborious tasks (provisioning, recovery and maintenance) using PowerShell, SCORCH and Chef.
- Was instrumental in devising an automated process to recover unused / underutilized VM instances saving \$.

Education:

BE Computer Science | Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College, Chennai, India | May 2008 – May 2012